Sooner or later they’ll find you.
The Others is a horror, mystery, thriller film directed by Alejandro Amenábar.
Grace is a religious woman who lives in an old house kept dark because her two
children, Anne and Nicholas, have a rare sensitivity to light.
When the family begins to suspect the house is haunted, Grace fights to protect her
children at any cost in the face of strange events and disturbing visions.
Grace Stewart, played by Nicole Kidman.
Anne Stewart, played by Alakina Mann.
Mrs. Bertha Mills, played by Fionnula Flanagan.
Nicholas Stewart, played by James Bentley.
Mr. Edmund Tuttle, played by Eric Sykes.
Charles Stewart, played by Christopher Eccleston.
The Others (Spanish: Los otros) is a 2001 psychological horror film written, directed and scored by Alejandro Amenábar, starring
Nicole Kidman, Fionnula Flanagan, Christopher Eccleston, Elaine Cassidy, Eric Sykes, Alakina Mann and James Bentley.
Set in 1945 in Jersey, it focuses on a woman and her two photosensitive children who
experience supernatural phenomena in their manor after the arrival of new servants.
The Others was theatrically released in the United States on August 10, 2001, by
Dimension Films, and in Spain on September 7, 2001, by Warner Sogefilms.
It was a major box-office success, grossing $210
million worldwide on a $17 million budget.
Critics praised the atmosphere, performances
(particularly Kidman) and its plot twist.
At the 16th Goya Awards, The Others earned a leading fifteen nominations and won in eight
categories, including Best Film, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.
It was the first English-language film without Spanish
dialogue to win Best Film at Spain's Goya Awards.
It received six nominations at the 28th Saturn Awards, winning Best Horror Film,
Best Actress (for Kidman), and Best Supporting Actress (for Flanagan).
It was nominated for Best Actress in a Leading Role (for Kidman) and Best Original Screenplay at the
55th British Academy Film Awards, and for Best Film at the 14th European Film Awards.
Kidman was nominated for Best Actress in a Motion Picture
– Drama at the 59th Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of nightmare, suicide
attempt, christianity, shotgun, servant.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.